(
"ai_sub_version": "3.6.0",
"generated_at": "2026-10-06T23:13:23.425239",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"service_tier": null,
"service_tier_subtitles": null,
"service_tier_lyrics": null,
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
ふぉっくす るーむ!!
FOXKINGDOM STORY SIDE ROOM
Fox Room!!
さくらみこ / 大空スバル
Miko Sakura / Subaru Oozora
風真いろは / 博衣こより
Iroha Kazama / Koyori Hakui
白銀ノエル / 雪花ラミィ
Noel Shirogane / Lamy Yukihana
百鬼あやめ / 大神ミオ
Ayame Nakiri / Mio Ookami
戌神ころね / 猫又おかゆ
Korone Inugami / Okayu Nekomata
常闇トワ / 沙花叉クロヱ
Towa Tokoyami / Chloe Sakamata
白上フブキ
Fubuki Shirakami
かわいい！ 絶対に かわいい！
Cute! Absolutely cute!
もっと甘やかして？
Pamper me more, okay?
頑張る理由、私でしょ？
I'm your reason for working hard, right?
何しても かわいいんだもん
Because no matter what I do, I'm just so cute!
今日も完璧な自分に酔っちゃおう
Today, let me get drunk on my perfect self again!
もっとドキドキして ねえ
Make my heart beat faster, okay?
もっと夢中になって ねえ
Get more obsessed with me, okay?
君に褒められるたび かわいくなる
Every time you praise me, I become even cuter!
ふわふわ とろとろ 頭の中 私だけ
Fluffy, melting... make your head filled only with me!
好きをお届け いいことずくめ 独占してね？
Delivering love, full of good things, monopolize me, okay?
きゅん きゅん きゅん
Kyun, kyun, kyun!
あざと かわいい！
Cunningly cute!
オトナ かわいい！
Adult-like cute!
変幻自在 かわいい！
Ever-changing cute!
一生一緒だよね？
We'll be together forever, right?
君にだけ 萌え萌えきゅん！
Only for you, moe moe kyun!
朝も かわいい！
Cute in the morning!
夜も かわいい！
Cute at night!
毎分毎秒 かわいい！
Cute every minute, every second!
全部が好きでしょ？
You love everything about me, don't you?
生まれつきの才能
A natural-born talent,
らぶりー属性 ちゅっ
my lovely attribute! *mwah*
目が離せなくなっちゃうでしょ？
You can't take your eyes off me, right?
世界に一人だけだもん
After all, I'm the only one in the world!
注がれた愛の分だけ 無敵になる
The more love I'm showered with, the more invincible I become!
世界一 あいうぉんちゅー
The world's biggest "I want you!"
宇宙一 あいにーじゅー
The universe's biggest "I need you!"
甘々な私を 大好きでしょ？
You love the spoiled me, don't you?
おバカ かわいい！
Silly and cute!
天然 かわいい！
Airhead and cute!
困るくらい かわいい！
Troublesomely cute!
まだまだ好きにさせちゃう
I'll make you fall even deeper in love!
君にだけ らぶらぶちゅっ
Only for you, love-love chu!
オンも かわいい！
Cute when I'm on-duty!
オフも かわいい！
Cute when I'm off-duty!
年中無休 かわいい！
Cute 365 days a year!
何回言っても 足りないんだから かわいい！
No matter how many times I say it, it's never enough! I'm cute!
はい！せーの！
Yes! One, two!
言いたいことがあるんだよ
There is something I want to tell you!
やっぱりフブキは可愛いよ
Fubuki is indeed so cute!
好き好き大好きやっぱ好き
Love you, love you, love you, indeed I love you!
やっと見つけたお姫様
The princess I've finally found!
俺が生まれてきた理由
The reason why I was born,
それはフブキに出会うため
was to meet Fubuki!
俺と一緒に人生歩もう
Let's walk through life together!
世界で一番愛してる！愛してる！
I love you most in the world! I love you!
でもね でもね
But you know, but you know...
君がいないと 始まんないんだよ
It doesn't start without you.
ずっと ずっと 私の隣にいてね
Always, always, stay by my side, okay?
ずーっと見てて？
Keep watching me forever, okay?
あざと かわいい！
Cunningly cute!
オトナ かわいい！
Adult-like cute!
変幻自在 かわいい！
Ever-changing cute!
一生一緒だよね？
We'll be together forever, right?
君にだけ 萌え萌えきゅん！
Only for you, moe moe kyun!
朝も かわいい！
Cute in the morning!
夜も かわいい！
Cute at night!
毎分毎秒 かわいい！
Cute every minute, every second!
全部が好きでしょ？
You love everything about me, don't you?
生まれつきの才能
A natural-born talent,
愛される天才
a genius at being loved,
らぶりー属性 ちゅっ
my lovely attribute! *mwah*
ライブ会場にお越しのすこん部の皆さん！
Everyone in the Sukon-bu here at the live venue!
こんばんきーつね！
Konban-kitsune!
ふわふわしっぽの五尾狐
The five-tailed fox with a fluffy tail,
あなたの心の一番星、白上フブキでーす！
the number one shining star in your heart, Shirakami Fubuki here!
はい、フレンズ！
Hi, friends!
本日は、白上の生誕ライブにお越しくださり、誠にありがとうございます！
Thank you all so much for coming to Fubuki's Birthday Live today!
今日のライブのテーマは、なんと…アイドル！
The theme of today's live is... Idol!
アイドル力全開のフブちゃんを、皆さん最後まで目に焼き付けてくださいね！
Everyone, please burn this Fubu-chan with full idol power into your eyes until the very end, okay?
ということで、今回のハッシュタグ、#ふぉっくするーむで
And so, please use today's hashtag, #Foxroom...
たくさんポストしてくださいね！
Please post a lot on social media!
それでは、次の曲もいってみましょう！
Now, let's move on to the next song!
ねぇねぇ、もしものもしもだよ？
Hey, hey, what if... just what if?
私が帰り道、グリズリーに襲われたら
On my way home, I was attacked by a grizzly bear?
あなたならどうする？
What would you do?
もしも もしも あなたならどうする？
What if, what if, what would you do?
イェーイ！
Yeah!
もしもね 帰り道 グリズリーに出逢っても
Even if I encounter a grizzly on my way home,
暗闇で 目が合えば 恐怖で 動けないわ
if our eyes meet in the dark, I'd be frozen with fear.
震える 唇で 「助けて」と電話したら
If I call you with trembling lips, saying "Help me!"
あなたは すぐに 来てくれますか？
Will you come to me right away?
ねえ 嘘つきって あしらわないで 真実なの お願い
Hey, don't dismiss me as a liar, it's the truth, please!
お願い！
Please!
パジャマだって 駆けつけてね
Even in pajamas, run to me.
1秒を争うのよ
Every second counts.
Yシャツに 着替える間に ほら丸呑みされちゃうわ
While you're changing into a shirt, look, I'll be swallowed whole.
Yes! Help!
裸足だって 駆けつけてね
Even barefoot, run to me,
私を疑う前に
before you doubt me.
心配でたまらなくて 走り出してほしいのです
Please run to me, so worried you can't help yourself.
そんな人が嬉しいの
I'd love someone like that.
イェーイ！
Yeah!
もしもね 曲がり角 グリズリーにぶつかり
What if, at a street corner, I bump into a grizzly?
物陰で 向き合えば 怖くて 叫べないわ
Facing it in the shadows, I'd be too scared to scream.
怯える 左手で 「助けて」とメールしたら
If I text you "Help me" with my trembling left hand...
あなたは すぐに 見てくれますか？
Will you read it right away?
ねえ ほら吹きって 片付けないで 本当なの 信じて
Hey, don't write me off as a braggart, it's real, believe me!
信じて！
Believe me!
仕事だって 駆けつけてね
Even from work, run to me.
何もかもを投げ出して
Throwing everything else aside.
残業が終わるまでに ほら丸呑みされちゃうわ
Before your overtime ends, look, I'll be swallowed whole.
Yes! Help!
どこにだって 駆けつけてね
Run to me, wherever you are,
私を疑う前に
before you doubt me.
居ても立っても居られない 取り乱してほしいのです
I want you to be so flustered that you can't sit still.
そんな人が愛しいの
I'd adore someone like that.
イェーイ！
Yeah!
ねぇ、もしもし？ 大変大変！
Hey, hello? This is bad, really bad!
帰り道にグリズリーがいるの！
There's a grizzly on my way home!
助けて！
Help me!
私、怖くて一歩も動けないよ！
I'm too scared to move even a single step!
今すぐ来て！助けて！
Come right now! Help me!
きゃー！こっちに来るよ！
Kyaa! It's coming this way!
私のこと見てる！ひぃー！
It's looking at me! Eek!
助けてよー！
Help me!
あーれー！
Nooo!
ねえ 嘘つきって あしらわないで 真実なの
Hey, don't dismiss me as a liar, it's the truth.
お願い
Please...
パジャマだって 駆けつけてね
Even in pajamas, run to me.
1秒を争うのよ
Every second counts.
Yシャツに 着替える間に ほら丸呑みされちゃうわ
While you're changing into a shirt, look, I'll be swallowed whole.
Yes! Help!
裸足だって 駆けつけてね
Even barefoot, run to me,
私を疑う前に
before you doubt me.
心配でたまらなくて 走り出ししてほしいのです
Please run to me, so worried you can't help yourself.
そんな人が嬉しいの
I'd love someone like that.
あなたしかいないの
There's only you.
ありがとう
Thank you!
Special♡Spell
[Song: Special♡Spell]
メトロで揺られる帰り道 また
On my way home, swaying on the subway,
今日も反省会
I hold another self-reflection meeting today.
意味ない そんなのわかってるもん
It's pointless, I know that already.
ほっといて！
Leave me alone!
だけど君が浮かんでサレンダー
But you pop into my head, and I surrender.
一瞬で笑顔へとアップデート
In an instant, I update to a smile.
昨日が煌めくほうが
Having a sparkling yesterday
どんなときだって正解
is always the right answer.
好きだけ集めてコトコト煮込んだままで
Gathering only what I love and simmering it,
溢れた涙もスパイスにしよう
let's turn the overflowing tears into spice too.
甘くて苦い私のすべて
My sweet and bitter everything,
君に知ってほしいの
I want you to know it all.
真剣タイム
Serious time!
答えはひとつじゃ...
The answer isn't just one...
お耳ついてる 可愛いでしょう？
I have ears on, cute, right?
きゅるりんと唱えて 秘密の呪文
Chant "Kyururin" - a secret spell,
スペシャルな魔法
a special magic.
林檎みたいに スウィーティースウィーティ
Sweet like an apple, sweety, sweety,
恋は禁断の罪の味
love is the taste of forbidden sin.
願って叶えて 奇跡を注文
Wish and fulfill, order a miracle,
スペシャルを希望
wishing for something special.
わがままでいいんです 女の子だもん
It's okay to be selfish, after all, I'm a girl.
舐めてもいいよ
You can even taste it.
いつも心配ばっか 悪い癖で
Always worrying, it's a bad habit.
適当に適当に生きていこ？
Let's just live lightheartedly, okay?
自分の機嫌を取るのも自分です
Keeping myself in a good mood is up to me too.
まあ もっとご褒美ちょうだいってな！
Well, give me even more rewards!
なんて悩んでいても
Even if I worry like that,
結局君の一言が全部 | in the end, a single word from you
in the end, a single word from you
あっさり解決しちゃうから
easily resolves everything.
なんかちょっとかなり ズルくて不満です
So I'm a little—actually, quite—unhappy with how unfair that is.
ぐるぐるネガティブの請求
Round and round, negative bills keeping coming,
色んなストレスの二重
doubling up on all kinds of stress.
ドキドキときめき I want you
My heart is throbbing and fluttering, I want you.
いつでも君だけ I love you
Anytime, it's only you, I love you.
どうかいつの日も忘れないで
Please, don't ever forget
スペシャルな魔法
this special magic.
最高のハッピーエンドへ ふさわしいヒロインはだれ？
Who is the heroine fit for the best happy ending?
私でしょ！
It's me, right!
きゅるりんと唱えて 秘密の呪文
Chant "Kyururin" - a secret spell,
スペシャルな魔法
a special magic.
林檎みたいに スウィーティースウィーティ
Sweet like an apple, sweety, sweety,
恋は禁断の罪の味
love is the taste of forbidden sin.
願って叶えて 奇跡を注文
Wish and fulfill, order a miracle,
世界一スペシャルを希望
wishing for the most special thing in the world.
わがままでいいんです 女の子だもん
It's okay to be selfish, after all, I'm a girl.
思うまま自由に 見るストーリー
A story I watch freely as I please.
さあ明日はどんな私になろう
Now, what kind of me will I become tomorrow?
魔法のジャムの隠し味は
The secret ingredient of the magic jam is...
だめ 教えてあげないの
No, I won't tell you.
えくちゅ おきゅーじょ とけちゃって奉仕
Excuse, serving you with a melting heart!
メイドイン愛のメイド
A maid made of love,
Cuto! 愛のメイド きゅきゅきゅ きゅん！
Cuto! A maid of love, squeeze, squeeze, squeeze, squee!
袖を通して即スイッチON
Put on the sleeves, switch instantly ON!
世界へ愛をふりまいちゃうんだ
Sprinkling love all over the world!
待って待って！ 猛烈注意報
Wait, wait! Intense warning!
待って待って！ 褒めなきゃ退場
Wait, wait! If you don't praise me, you're out!
ご主人様もお嬢様のことも ドキッとさせて心をお掃除
Making both Masters and Princesses skip a beat, cleaning their hearts!
待って待って！ 持ち時間15秒
Wait, wait! Remaining time: 15 seconds!
待って待って！ ミルクもトイレも
Wait, wait! Milk and toilet too!
毎日頑張ってるもん！ いたしていいでしょ？
I'm doing my best every day! So it's okay to spoil me, right?
もっと伝われ 伝われ 目を離しちゃダメ
Connect more, reach you more, don't take your eyes off me!
あざとい顔して はにゃはにゃ
Making a cute, calculated face, hanyan-hanyan!
君とワンツーでギュンです あちゅあちゅ夢中です
With you, one-two, my heart goes squeeze! Hot, hot, I'm so into you!
頭クラクラくらい
To the point my head is spinning!
泣いちゃってじゃないよ 何でもしちゃおう
I'm not crying! Let's do whatever we want!
でも私ピュアすぎ
But I'm way too pure!
ちゅちゅちゅ ちゅちゅちゅ 君のために
Chu-chu-chu, chu-chu-chu, for you!
決まり 事実 私のために
It's decided, it's a fact! For me!
えくちゅ おきゅーじょ とけちゃって奉仕 メイドイン愛のメイド
Excuse, serving you with a melting heart! A maid made of love,
くりてぃかるぷりちー きゅきゅきゅ きゅん！
Critical Pretty, squeeze, squeeze, squeeze, squee!
考えらんなくなっちゃって もうね メラメラ ジー！
I can't even think anymore, staring intensely, jee!
自己採点 常に満点
My self-score is always a perfect score!
ラブはいい？ めっちゃいい？ 甘すぎ すっぱい！
Is love good? Super good? Too sweet, sour!
気絶しちゃうほどの ラブアンケートいかが？
How about a love survey so intense you'll faint?
招待！
Invitation!
すぐに飲んじゃう
I swallow it right away,
健気だよね
so admirable, isn't it?
もっと優しく 優しく
Be more gentle, gentle,
手を繋いでいて
hold my hand,
マイフーフー
my hoo-hoo.
毎秒1秒1秒
Every second, every single second...
君を独占中デス
I'm monopolizing you!
壊れる寸前
On the verge of breaking down,
ココふわふわで触りた〜いっ
It's so fluffy here, I want to touch it!
私なしじゃ生きられないよ
You can't live without me,
好きになるおまじない
Here's a spell to make you love me!
ハイッ、ピース！
Hi, peace!
君がバーン！
You, bang!
ハートにグー！
A punch to the heart!
何をしてても一級のフェイバリット
No matter what you do, you're a first-class favorite!
愛してくれてるから頑張れる
Because you love me, I can do my best.
二人でいて成り立つアットホーム
Being together makes us feel at home.
とことんベタベタ 最強コンボ！
Totally clingy, the strongest combo!
まだ足りなくない？もっと欲しくない？
Isn't it still not enough? Don't you want more?
私のところにおいで
Come to my side!
君と私でキュンです
You and me, our hearts go kyun!
頭クラクラでクラクラりしそう
My head is spinning, I'm about to fall dizzy!
なっちゃってんじゃないよ 何だってしちゃうよ
Don't just let it happen, I'll do anything!
ちょっと待って私ピュアすぎ
Wait a second, I'm too pure!
純粋に！従順に！君のために！
Purely! Obediently! Just for you!
つまり！実質！私のため！
In other words, practically, for my sake!
E級 F級 Q級 溶けちゃって欲しい
E-class, F-class, Q-class, I want them to melt!
迷い込む愛の迷宮
Straying into the labyrinth of love,
くりてぃかるぷりちー キュキュキュ キュン！
Critical Pretty! Kyu-kyu-kyu kyun!
焼き付けて
Burn it into your mind,
この繚乱の高揚を
this chaotic exhilaration.
Wow...
太陽は知らない 月には届かない
The sun doesn't know, and it doesn't reach the moon.
絶望も希望も 震える鼓動も
Both despair and hope, and even this trembling heartbeat.
ざわめく人ごみの まとわりつく温度
The clinging warmth of the bustling crowd,
今だけは心地よくなるの
just for now, it starts to feel pleasant.
遠雷に似た
Resembling distant thunder,
合図が響く
a signal echoes.
逸る想いと 呼び合うように
As if calling out to my rushing thoughts,
感じさせてよ
let me feel it,
もっと
even more...
愛を
of your love.
暗闇に咲く葛藤と 見つめ合っていたい
I want to lock eyes with the conflict blooming in the dark.
沈黙を破って 降りそそぐたび
Breaking the silence, every time it pours down,
心 儚さに揺れて
my heart sways in transience.
鬱陶しいくらいの 熱量に あぁ
With an almost annoying level of heat, ah,
もう少し浮かされていたいな
I want to remain entranced a little longer.
息を呑んで
Hold your breath,
そらさないで
don't look away.
忘れたくない繚乱の高揚を
I don't want to forget this chaotic exhilaration.
Wow...
この先何年も 思い出すのでしょう
For years to come, we'll surely remember
らしくない君の 汗伝う横顔
your sweat-streaked profile, so unlike you.
木下闇の下やみから覗く 裏腹な
Peeking from beneath the deep shade of trees, a contrary
眼差しは 何を見ていたの？
gaze—what were you looking at?
星の軌跡を 夜風が融かす
The night breeze melts the stars' trajectories,
うたた心を くすぐるように
as if to tickle my drifting heart.
忘れさせてよ
Let me forget
こんな憂いを
all of this sorrow.
擦れた裸足の 切なさも
Even the pain in my scraped bare feet
気にならないくらい
is completely forgotten.
お揃いで買った飴がけの
The candy-coated jewels
宝石を 舌で遊ばせて
we bought together, rolling on our tongues.
第三者目線じゃ 取るに足らない
In the eyes of a bystander, it's trivial,
瞬間が たまらなく愛しいの
but this moment is unbearably precious to me.
終わらないで
Don't let it end,
明けるまで
until the break of dawn.
トキメキと喧騒に溺れたい
I want to drown in the excitement and clamor.
花の命は なんて言って
Musing about the fleeting life of a flower,
色に出でにけり感情を 諦めたくない
I don't want to give up on emotions shown on my face.
沈黙を破って
Breaking the silence,
あまのじゃくな瞳の
of my contrary eyes,
その奥に触れて
reach deep inside them.
手と手合わせて 暗闇に咲く 葛藤と
Hand in hand, with the conflicts blooming in the darkness,
見つめ合っていたい
I want to keep gazing into your eyes.
不意に訪れる
Suddenly coming upon us,
引き足の静けさに
in the quietness of retreating footsteps,
気づかない振りして
I pretend not to notice.
鬱陶しいくらいの
With a heat so intense
熱量に もう少し
it's almost annoying, for just a bit longer,
浮かされていたいな
I want to be carried away.
息を呑んで
Hold your breath,
焼き付けて
burn it into your memory,
忘れたくない 繚乱の高揚を
I don't want to forget this blooming excitement.
Woo...
最高の最後まで 目を逸らさないで
Don't look away, until the very, very end.
もしもしダーリン
[Song: Moshi Moshi Darling]
もしもしDarlin' もしもしLove Rabbit もしもしKiss Kitty
Hello Darlin', hello Love Rabbit, hello Kiss Kitty
ハートはStrawberry
My heart is a strawberry.
もしもしMy Darling
Hello, my Darling.
この番号は ただいま恋の留守電中
This number is currently on a love voicemail.
ねぇ キミは
Hey, you...
知らないんでしょ？
...probably don't know, right?
女の子は
Girls are...
魔法で出来てる
...made of magic!
好きなもの？
Things I like?
好きな人は？
The person I like?
よそ見なんて出来ないくらい
So much that you can't look away,
いつだってプリンセス
I'm always your princess.
鏡よ鏡
Mirror, mirror,
世界で一番
show me the one who is...
輝くわたし 映して
...the brightest in the world!
過去の投稿一括非表示 だって！
Hiding all my past posts, because...
いつも可愛い更新中
...I'm always updating my cuteness!
イニシャルにイカした ♡のマーク
A cool heart mark on your initials,
こんなにキミが 大好きなのは
the fact that I love you this much...
秘密です
...is a secret!
二人しか知らない
Only the two of us know
Sweet talk
our sweet talk.
ああ 神様の言う通りにはしない
Ah, we won't do as God says!
もしもし？聞こえる？
Hello? Can you hear me?
もしもし？I love you...
Hello? I love you...
もしもしMy Darling もしもしLove Rabbit もしもしKiss Kitty
Hello My Darling, hello Love Rabbit, hello Kiss Kitty
ハートはStrawberry
My heart is a strawberry.
もしもしMy Darling
Hello, my Darling.
この番号は ただいま恋の留守電中
This number is currently on a love voicemail.
四六時中
Twenty-four seven,
構ってほしい
I want your attention!
募るメッセージ
Messages piling up,
未読はタブー
leaving them unread is a taboo!
お決まりの
Our usual
大反省会
big reflection meeting.
止まらない後悔
Regrets that won't stop...
どうしよう また病んじゃう
What should I do? I'm getting sick of this again!
世界中をすべて
Painting the whole world
ピンク色に塗り替えて
completely in pink,
わたしの好き 全肯定
fully validating everything I love!
ねぇ？ずっと
Hey, we're always
想像裏切る計画中
planning to defy all expectations!
早く見つけてよ 会いたいのサイン
Find it quickly, my sign of wanting to see you.
こんなにキミが 鈍感なのは
The fact that you are this dense...
誤算です
...is a miscalculation!
お揃いの迷子で
Getting lost together,
Sweet Heart
ああ ハッピーエンドの続きなんていらない
Ah, I don't need a sequel to our happy ending!
もしもし？聞いてる？
Hello? Are you listening?
もしもし？I hate you...
Hello? I hate you...
むかしむかしあるところに
Once upon a time, in a certain place...
お姫様がいました
there was a princess.
お姫様は言いました
The princess said:
誰かのために可愛くなるんじゃない
"I don't become cute for someone else's sake."
わたしはわたしの為に可愛くなるの！
"I become cute for my own sake!"
むかしむかしあるところに
Once upon a time, in a certain place...
お姫様がいました
there was a princess.
お姫様は言いました
The princess said:
誰かのために可愛くなるんじゃない
"I don't become cute for someone else's sake."
わたしはわたしの為に可愛くなるの！
"I become cute for my own sake!"
唯一無二の物語
Our one-of-a-kind story,
描くのは 誰？
who is the one writing it?
生まれ変わってもまたわたしになりたい
Even if I'm reborn, I want to be myself again,
絶対に！
absolutely!
イニシャルにイカした ♡のマーク
A cool heart mark on your initials,
こんなにキミが 大好きなのは
the fact that I love you this much...
秘密です
...is a secret!
二人しか知らない
Only the two of us know
Sweet talk
our sweet talk.
ああ 神様の言う通りにはしない
Ah, we won't do as God says!
もしもし？聞こえる？
Hello? Can you hear me?
もしもし？I love you...
Hello? I love you...
もしもしMy Darling もしもしLove Rabbit もしもしKiss Kitty
Hello My Darling, hello Love Rabbit, hello Kiss Kitty
ハートはStrawberry
My heart is a strawberry.
もしもしMy Darling
Hello, my Darling.
この番号は ただいま恋の留守電中
This number is currently on a love voicemail.
See you later
ray
[Song: ray]
お別れしたのはもっと前のことだったような
It feels like it's been much longer since we said goodbye.
悲しい光は封じ込めて 踵すり減らしたんだ
Locking away that sad light, wearing down my heels.
Oh...
君といた時は見えた 今は見えなくなった
I could see it when I was with you, but now it's gone.
透明な彗星をぼんやりと でもそれだけ探している
Faintly, I search for that invisible comet, but that's all I look for.
シャッターを切ったよ その時だけのメロディーを
I pressed the shutter, capturing a melody unique to that moment.
寂しくなんかなかったよ ちゃんと寂しくなれたから
I wasn't lonely at all, because I was able to properly feel the loneliness.
いつまでどこまでなんて 正常か異常かなんて
"Until when, how far..." "Is this normal or abnormal?"
考える暇もないほど 歩くのは大変だ
It's so hard to keep walking, there's no time to even think.
楽しい方がずっといいよ ごまかして笑っていくよ
Having fun is much better, so I'll hide my feelings and keep smiling.
大丈夫だ あの痛みは 忘れたって消えやしない
It's alright, even if I forget that pain, it will never disappear.
理想で作った道を 現実が塗り替えていくよ
Reality paints over the path built by ideals.
思い出はその軌跡の上で 輝きになって残っている
Memories remain on that trajectory, turning into a guiding light.
お別れしたのはなんで なんでのためだったんだろうな
Why did we say goodbye? What on earth was it all for?
悲しい光が僕の影を 前に長く伸ばしている
The sad light casts my shadow long ahead of me.
時々熱が出るよ 時間がある時に眠るよ
Sometimes I run a fever, and I sleep whenever I can.
夢だとわかるその中で 君と会ってからまた行こう
Knowing it's a dream, I'll meet you there before moving on again.
晴天とはほど遠い 終わらない暗闇にも
Even in an endless darkness, far from a clear blue sky,
星を思い浮かべたなら すぐに銀河の中だ
If I picture the stars, I'm instantly in the middle of a galaxy.
あまり泣かなくなっても 靴を新しくしても
Even if I don't cry as much anymore, even with brand new shoes,
大丈夫だ あの痛みは 忘れたって消えやしない
It's alright, even if I forget that pain, it will never disappear.
伝えたかったことがきっと あったんだろうな
There must have been things I wanted to tell you.
おそらくだいたいそんなのだろうけど こんなにも
It's probably something like that, but even so, it's so much...
お別れしたことは 出会ったことと繋がっている
Saying goodbye is connected to our meeting in the first place.
あの透明な彗星は 透明だからなくならない
That invisible comet can never be lost, because it's invisible.
〇×△どれかなんて 皆と比べてどうかなんて
"Correct, wrong, or in-between," "How do I compare to others?"
確かめる間もないほど 生きるのが最高だ
There's no time to verify, living is just the absolute best.
あまり泣かなくなっても ごまかして笑っていくよ
Even if I don't cry as much anymore, I'll hide my feelings and keep smiling.
大丈夫だ あの痛みは 忘れたって消えやしない
It's alright, even if I forget that pain, it will never disappear.
大丈夫だ この光の始まりには 君がいる
It's alright, at the very beginning of this light, you are there.
この世界メイズ 誰かが見ている
This world is a maze, someone is watching...
心の中のケージ
A cage inside the heart.
ここは低イメージ
Here is a low-res image,
固まったフェイス
a frozen face.
異変探すレース
A race to find anomalies,
秘め閉じ込めたケージ
a cage locked away with secrets.
君の書いた発明
The invention you wrote down...
夢を見るのはいつ以来？
How long has it been since I last dreamed?
不意に始まる紙芝居
A picture story show starts unexpectedly.
ここを出るにはどれくらい？
How much longer until I can get out of here?
0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8
イエス！
Yes!
夢を見るのはいつ以来？
How long has it been since I last dreamed?
不意に始まる意味深アイ
A meaningful scene starts unexpectedly.
ここを出るにはどれくらい？
How much longer until I can get out of here?
0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8
この世界メイズ 誰かが見ている
This world is a maze, someone is watching...
心の中のケージ
A cage inside the heart.
ここは低イメージ
Here is a low-res image,
固まったフェイス
a frozen face.
異変探すレース
A race to find anomalies,
秘め閉じ込めたケージ
a cage locked away with secrets.
君の書いた発明
The invention you wrote down...
夢を見るのはいつ以来？
How long has it been since I last dreamed?
不意に始まる紙芝居
A picture story show starts unexpectedly.
ここを出るにはどれくらい？
How much longer until I can get out of here?
0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8
キャー！
Kyaa!
息を吸い込ませて
Make me inhale,
押し込むリセット
and push the reset.
迷い込む迷路
Wandering into a maze,
進めど戻る迷路
a maze where I return no matter how far I go.
ドアの先に僕の背中が見えた
Beyond the door, I saw my own back.
振り向いた先に希望が見えた
Turning around, I saw a glimpse of hope.
地獄の果てなどどこにあるんだ
Where on earth is the end of this hell?
出口はまだなの
Is there still no exit?
くるくる くるくる くりかえす
Round and round, repeating...
くりかえす
Repeating,
repeating,
くりかえす
repeating.
ふらふら ふらふら ふらくだる
Dizzy and wandering in a fractal...
ふらくだる
Fractal,
fractal,
ふらくだる
fractal.
空回る外
The outside spinning in vain,
終わらないロンド
an endless rondo.
鉄格子 酸素
Iron bars, oxygen,
届かない SOS
an SOS that doesn't reach.
落ちてた袋で飢えを凌いだ
Staving off hunger with a discarded bag,
頭蓋の中から耳鳴りがした
a ringing sound echoed inside my skull.
進めど 進めど 変わりないなら
If nothing changes no matter how far I go...
からからと耳鳴りと
Rattling, with a ringing in my ears
くるくる くりかえす
Spinning and spinning, repeating
くりかえす くりかえす くりかえす
repeating, repeating, repeating
ふらふら ふらくだる
Dizzy and dizzy, stumbling down
ふらくだる ふらくだる ふらくだる
stumbling down, stumbling down, stumbling down
あ、扉を開け 意味も忘れ
Ah, open the door, forgetting all meaning
いかれた夢の奥へ
Into the depths of a mad dream
どこまでも続いていく
Continuing on forever...
くるくる くりかえす
Spinning and spinning, repeating
ブラフマン
[Brahman]
さあ 魂 騙して 剥がして 縛り付けて
Now, deceive my soul, strip it away, and bind it down
魂 交わして 天変地異で左様なら
Exchange our souls, and say goodbye amidst cataclysm
悲しい話して 楽しいね 期待込めて
Telling sad stories is so much fun, filled with anticipation
やっと列を成す母性愛だ
Maternal love is finally forming a line
一刻も早く盲従 あなたに会いたい
Blindly obeying as quickly as possible, I want to see you
まるで ルマ・マシャンの箱庭 期待だらけの機械
Just like a Rumah Macan miniature garden, a machine full of expectations
一刻も早く盲従 抗いたい未来
Blindly obeying as quickly as possible, a future I want to resist
閉ざされた欲の住処を這えば
If I crawl through the locked dwelling of desire...
相乗り 乗りになったダンスミュージック
Carpooling with the rhythm, dance music
パラノイア 肥らせて 精々で 有名に させて
Fattening the paranoia, make me famous at best
世界 重い重い まるで バンブルビー
The world is heavy, heavy, just like a bumblebee
蜂の自慢 穿らせて 精々で 有名に させて
Letting the bee's pride burrow, make me famous at best
あぁ 相棒だ 僕らは 僕らは 酔い惑い行くばっかだ
Ah, we are partners, we do nothing but wander drunkenly
信じるかい？無いかい？差なんて 手のひら羅針盤に頼る
Do you believe? Is there no difference? Relying on the compass in our palms
何度も 何度も 懲りずに 恋をしまして
Again and again, without learning, falling in love
ハートビート繰り返すポンコツ 精々で
A piece of junk repeating its heartbeat, at best
さあ 魂 騙して 馬鹿見て 合点いって
Now, deceive my soul, play the fool, and understand it all
魂失くして 精々で左様なら
Lose your soul, and say goodbye at best
また 悲しい話して 貧しいね 期待外れ
Telling sad stories again, how pitiful, disappointing
意志の否定をして こちらへおいで
Denying your own will, come over here
踏み出しても明日は明日のまま
Even if we step forward, tomorrow remains tomorrow
はみ出しても界は界のまま
Even if we stick out, the boundary remains the boundary
当然の帰結がライフ 生命の不滅は無い
Life is the natural consequence, there is no immortality for life
踏み出しても明日は明日のまま
Even if we step forward, tomorrow remains tomorrow
一刻も早く盲従 あなたに会いたい
Blindly obeying as quickly as possible, I want to see you
枯れた夢の続きを 愛して くれるなら
If you will love the continuation of this withered dream
一刻も早く盲従 抗いたい未来
Blindly obeying as quickly as possible, a future I want to resist
欠けた心の隙間を 埋めるなら
If you will fill the gap in my broken heart...
ららら...
La la la...
乗り乗りになったダンスミュージック
Carpooling with the rhythm, dance music
パラノイア 肥らせて 精々で 有名に させて
Fattening the paranoia, make me famous at best
世界 重い重い まるで バンブルビー
The world is heavy, heavy, just like a bumblebee
蜂の自慢 穿らせて 精々で 有名に させて
Letting the bee's pride burrow, make me famous at best
乗り乗りになったブラフマンに
Into the grooving Brahman
パラノイア 肥らせて 精々で 有名に させて
Fattening the paranoia, make me famous at best
世界 重い重い まるで バンブルビー
The world is heavy, heavy, just like a bumblebee
蜂の自慢 穿らせて 精々で 有名に させて
Letting the bee's pride burrow, make me famous at best
あぁ 僕らは 僕らは 酔い惑い行くばっかだ
Ah, we are partners, we do nothing but wander drunkenly
信じるかい？無いかい？差なんて 手のひら羅針盤に頼る
Do you believe? Is there no difference? Relying on the compass in our palms
何度も 何度も 懲りずに 恋をしまして
Again and again, without learning, falling in love
ハートビート繰り返すポンコツ
A piece of junk repeating its heartbeat
酷々と精々で
Cruelly and at best
ここはきっと夢の中ね
This must be inside a dream
FOXXXROOM
目覚めたのは 嘘みたいだ
Waking up feels like a lie
知らないはずの部屋
A room I shouldn't know
振り返れば いくつもの目が
If I look back, countless eyes...
私を見つめていました
...were staring at me
目指したのは 温かかった
What I aimed for was warm
私がいるはずの場所
The place where I should be
目の前には ただ広がる
Before my eyes, it simply spreads out
まるで心の中みたいな
Just like the inside of my heart
コンコンコンと扉の先
Knock, knock, knock, beyond the door
繰り返すループ 木霊した音
Repeating loop, an echoing sound
コンコンコンと笑い声
Knock, knock, knock, and the sound of laughter
狐の少女が手招いてた
The fox girl was beckoning
ああ どうかそのまま
Ah, please, just like that...
この気持ちのエンドまで
To the end of this feeling,
連れて行って！ 連れて行って！
take me with you, take me with you!
逃げ出したいよ 抜け出したいから
I want to run away, because I want to escape.
いくつも扉開けた
I've opened so many doors.
逃げ出したいよ 抜け出したいのに
I want to run away, even though I want to escape.
わからない かわらない わからないな
I don't know, it doesn't change, I just don't know.
ここはきっと夢の中ね
Surely, this place is inside a dream.
寂しくひとり歩いてました
I was walking alone in loneliness.
戻ろうとしたら怒られました
When I tried to turn back, I was scolded.
大事なことを忘れました
I forgot something important.
「出口はこちら」と言われました
"The exit is this way," I was told.
おかしな部屋に入りました
I entered a strange room.
仕方ないので進みました
Having no choice, I kept moving forward.
疲れたけど また見たのは
Though I was tired, what I saw again...
知らないはずの部屋だった
...was a room I shouldn't have known.
コンコンコンと扉の向こう
Tap-tap-tap, beyond the door.
終わらないループ ため息つき
An endless loop, letting out a sigh.
コンコンコンと笑う声
With a laugh of "kon, kon, kon,"
狐の少女は前を行った
the fox girl walked ahead of me.
ああ はやくこのまま
Ah, hurry, just like this,
この迷路のエンドまで
to the end of this labyrinth.
連れて行って
Take me with you.
おねがい
Please.
逃げ出したいよ
I want to run away.
抜け出したいから
Because I want to escape.
辿り着くと信じて
Believing I will reach the end,
逃げ出したいよ
I want to run away.
抜け出したいよ
I want to escape.
わからない かわらない わからない
I don't know, it doesn't change, I don't know.
わからない
I don't know.
逃げ出したいよ
I want to run away.
抜け出したいから
Because I want to escape.
見つけた光はそこに
The light I found is right there.
逃げ出したんだ
I ran away.
抜け出したんだ
I escaped.
少女は静かに微笑んでた
The girl was smiling quietly.
ここがきっと夢の終わり
Surely, this place is the end of the dream.
最後の扉
The final door.
目の前には 嘘みたいな
Before my eyes lies a room like a lie,
知らないはずの部屋
a room I shouldn't know.
振り返れば 少女は消えた
When I looked back, the girl had vanished.
私ずっと
All along, I've been...
夢の中ね
...inside a dream, haven't I?
皆さん、こんばんは！
Good evening, everyone!
王立図書館にて私、司書しております。
I work as a librarian at the Royal Library.
なんだか先ほどのライブから自宅に帰ってこないすこん部がいるという噂が
It seems there are rumors that some Sukonbu haven't returned home since the live performance earlier...
王国内に広まってるようだね。
...and these rumors are spreading throughout the kingdom.
まあ、この件に関しての解決は
Well, as for resolving this matter,
もしかすると、あの方々が動いてる可能性が...
it's possible that those people are already on the move...
まあ、それは別のお話で。
Well, that's a story for another time.
では、ここからは私がご案内させていただきます！
Now, allow me to guide you through the rest!
白上フブキ生誕記念2026グッズのご紹介です！
Here is the introduction of the Shirakami Fubuki Birthday Celebration 2026 merchandise!
まず1つ目！
First of all!
「FOXXROOM アクリルジオラマスタンド」
"FOXXROOM Acrylic Diorama Stand"!
セイント衣装のアクリルジオラマスタンドです。
This is an acrylic diorama stand featuring the Saint outfit.
イラストは灸場メロ先生に描いていただきました！
The illustration was drawn by Melo Kyuba-sensei!
この世界へ繋がる扉は、
The door connecting to this world...
あなたのすぐそばにあるのかもね。
...might be right beside you.
続いては、「王国缶バッジ セイントver.」です！
Next is the "Kingdom Badge Saint ver."!
キービジュアルを使用した缶バッジ。
A button badge featuring the key visual.
本体にキラキラホログラム加工と、フレームデザインはジュエリー箔押し加工になっております。
With a glittering hologram processing on the badge itself, and jewelry gold foil stamping on the frame.
この高級感、素敵ですよね。
This premium feel is wonderful, isn't it?
続いては、「FBKINGDOM 騎士団法被」！
Next up is the "FBKINGDOM Knight Order Happi"!
王国騎士団員をイメージした法被です。
This happi coat is inspired by the members of the Royal Knights.
原案は国女王様がデザインを、
The original concept was designed by her Majesty the Queen,
ブラッシュアップデザインをHyde先生が手がけました。
and Hyde-sensei did the brush-up design.
背中の騎士団ロゴ、そして裾の燕尾服がとても素敵ですよね。
The Knight Order logo on the back and the swallowtail hem look very stylish!
黒さんの部下の皆様は、ぜひお手元に！
All of you subordinates of Kuro, please grab one!
続いては、「すこん部ルームライト」です！
Next is the "Sukonbu Room Light"!
LEDの色は2色あり、もちっとした素材を使用しております。
The LED light has two colors and is made of a soft, squishy material.
インテリアとしてもよし、温かい光に包まれてくださいね。
Great as room decor, please let yourself be enveloped by its warm light.
フルセット購入特典として、チェキ風ブロマイドカードがついてきます！
As a full set purchase bonus, you'll receive a cheki-style bromide card!
数量限定は、直筆サイン＆箔押し複製メッセージ入り！
The limited-quantity version includes a hand-written autograph & foil-stamped printed message!
通常版は、箔押し複製サイン＆メッセージ入りです！
The standard version has a foil-stamped printed autograph & message!
王国民の皆様は、グッズサイトのご確認をよろしくお願いいたします！
Everyone in the kingdom, please check out the merchandise site!
続いてはこちら！
Next is this!
先ほどの生誕ライブにてお披露...
Revealed during the birthday live earlier...
お待たせしました。新曲「FOXX ROOM」が...
The wait is over! My new song, "FOXX ROOM"...
10月6日 24時にリリースされます。
...will be released on October 6th at midnight!
さらに！この後、22時30分より...
Furthermore, starting tonight at 10:30 PM...
FOXX ROOMのMVも公開予定！
...the music video for "FOXX ROOM" is also scheduled to premiere!
何気なく過ごす日常の隣にある世界を、ぜひお楽しみください。
Please enjoy this world that exists right beside our everyday lives.
続いてはこちらをご覧ください。
Next up, please take a look at this!
10月10日
[On-Screen: October 10th]
思い出の地に
[On-Screen: To the place of memories...]
王、降臨。
[On-Screen: ...the King descends.]
いいか、よく聞け！
Listen up, and listen closely!
みろくの里を、フブキングダムの領土とする！
I declare Miroku no Sato to be part of the Fubukingdom!
よし！ここに王の証を残してやる！
Alright! I shall leave proof of my kingship right here!
ここには等身大パネルを！
Let's put a life-sized standee over here!
見よ、この絶景！これが全部、白上たちのものなんだぜ。
Behold this magnificent view! All of this belongs to Fubuki and her friends.
うえーーい！
Yee-haw!
みろくの里とフブキングダムは、ずっと友だちだよ！
Miroku no Sato and Fubukingdom will be friends forever!
はい！ということで「フブキングダムの里」いよいよ10月10日よりオープンです！
Yes! And with that, "Fubukingdom no Sato" is finally opening on October 10th!
今流したホログラは、10月11日から放送予定。ぜひ本編見てみてください！
The HoloGra episode we just showed is scheduled to air on October 11th. Please watch the full episode!
いやー、フブキングダムがついに外に飛び出していくなんて嬉しいですね！
Wow, I'm so happy to see Fubukingdom finally expand into the real world!
白上描き下ろしのステッカーがもらえるスタンプラリーや...
There's a stamp rally where you can get a sticker illustrated by me...
ここでしか聴けない曲もある、全編撮り下ろしのライブ！
...and a newly recorded live concert featuring songs you can only hear here!
広島バージョンのすこん部ぬいぐるみをはじめとする、可愛いグッズの数々など...
A wide variety of cute merchandise will be available, including a Sukonbu plushie in a Hiroshima outfit...
現地にはお楽しみのコンテンツが盛りだくさん！
...offering plenty of exciting attractions to enjoy on-site!
また、メッセージボードも設置してもらいます！
Also, there will be a message board set up for you!
必ず帰国報告をしてくださいね！
Make sure to leave your homeland return reports there!
開催期間は11月3日までです。みなさんの帰国、待ってますよ！
The event runs until November 3rd. I'll be waiting for you all to return to your homeland!
続いてはこちらです！
Next up is this!
王国で過ごす かけがえのない日々
The irreplaceable days spent in the kingdom...
僕たちの物語に、新たな一ページが記される。
...write a brand new page in our story.
コラボレーションブースターパック 発売決定！
[On-Screen: Collaboration Booster Pack Release Confirmed!]
ああ？カード？いやだよ、めんどくせぇ。
Huh? A card game? No way, that's such a pain.
フブキングダムとホロライブオフィシャルカードゲームとのコラボが決定です！
A collaboration between Fubukingdom and the hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME has been confirmed!
相棒は...ふっ、気難しくてもなんだかんだあの人は...
My partner is... Heh, even though she's hard to please, deep down she's...
っと、今後の情報に乞うご期待です！
Whoops! Please look forward to more information in the future!
告知は以上です。
That's all for the announcements.
では皆さん、またどこかでお会いしましょう！
Well then, everyone, let's meet again somewhere!